Uh, all right. Thanks for uh thanks for
sticking with us tonight. Um, you know,
exciting night for us. Um, we're
excited. We very excited to add
Jeremiah. Um, you know, happened
happened quick there. We had to wait for
two picks and uh we're excited to to
call him and and let him know that he'd
be joining us. Just um excited about the
player, excited about the person, um you
know, excited about what he's going to
add to our team. So, um with that, I'll
shoot it to you guys. He said you guys
had a conversation last week and it went
really well that you know it was just
you guys hit it off right away. What was
it about the dynamic that you think
worked so well and
>> I mean he's he's I mean you guys will
get a chance to meet him tomorrow. Um
he's just an impressive kid. Uh mature.
Um has his head on his shoulders never
gets too high, never gets too low. Um
you know we had a great interaction with
him at the combine. um you know, I
followed up with him with a uh with a
call over the weekend and um yeah, just
had a had a great overall interaction.
So, you know, like I said, you guys will
get a chance to meet him. Impressive
kid. Um you know, just really excited to
add the person to our locker room.
>> We don't know a ton about your offense
yet, but what his how does he fit? How
does his skill set fit into what you
envision yourself doing? Yeah, I mean
like I I've said this with running
backs, you know, um they do come in all
shapes and sizes. What's what's unique
about him in my opinion is in all three
phases. And what I mean by all three
phases, the run game, the pass game, and
protection, you know, he's he has the
ability to to, you know, mix it in in
all those, you know. So, you guys see
all the explosive stuff. I mean, that
that's all there, you know, but uh you
know, he didn't have that weakness in my
opinion in any of those phases. So, you
can put him in those situations. You
know, he's got to learn this game. He's
got to learn the NFL. He's got to learn
the speed of it. I mean, there's a lot
still that that uh needs to be uh
learned in practice and all that, but uh
he definitely has the tools to get
there.
>> Monte, obviously uh when you're picking
that high in the draft, there's a lot of
conversation about premium positions and
running back. How did you measure that
or was it just a question of Jeremiah
being that much better than everybody
else?
>> Yeah, I think Darren with that, you
know, we're we're evaluating each each
player, each position. We're stacking
our board. Um, you know, when we're
picking that high, the the goal is to
add an impact player and um, you know,
there were there were certainly other
players that we talked about. Um, you
know, we did we talked about the
position. Uh, understand all that. In
the end, we we felt we added the guy
that could impact our team the most. Um,
and just really excited about the
versatility that he brings to the
offense.
it it's obviously generally easier and
and cheaper to find running backs
through other means, especially free
agency, than it is offensive tackles and
rushers. I guess like how much did that
play into your thinking and and what
made you willing to overlook um kind of
that element of of um I guess scarcity
at different positions? Um, I mean
really tail, I mean I think with every
decision that we make, we uh in the
draft we take the best player that we
think is available when we pick and we
did that tonight. That'll always be the
case. Um, and that's that will always be
the case as as long as I'm here. I know
that's what Mike believes in. It's what
I believe in and that's what we did.
>> How do you see the running back room
sorting itself out being a little bit
crowded now?
>> Yeah, it is. It's a it's a good room.
There's no question. and it's a good
room and I think with with as with
anything else the the competition will
take care of itself. Um you know so
that'll be for Mike and his staff to to
sort out but you know it's a it's a good
problem to have.
>> The two picks ahead of you kind of went
a little bit quick just in terms of the
clock getting down. You guys obviously
kind of went down to the final minute.
Could you just talk through maybe the
the trade conversations that you had?
Did you guys come close to moving out of
the pick? Like how did those go?
>> Yeah, Donnie you want if you want me to
tell you the honest god truth. we had
the wrong phone number to uh the the the
phone number that we were given was the
wrong one and so that was a little bit
of the delay. So we got that
straightened out and we called Jeremiah
and we got a hold of him. That's that's
what the delay was. Um
>> there was no delay.
>> There was no delay. Yeah. Um technical
difficulties. Um you know there was a
very minimal conversations Donnie. There
was you know some surface level but but
nothing that came anywhere close to to
getting us to move off the pick. Did you
have any conversations about moving back
into the first round 34 there?
>> Yeah, we did. We did late in the draft.
Um, you know, we kicked it around. Um,
you know, I think I told you guys the
other day, you start um you start
counting the number of players that you
would pick. Um, you know, and you look
at it and you look at there was a number
of teams that were looking, you guys saw
there was a lot of movement there at the
end of the first round. Um, so yeah, we
had we had some conversations. Um, but,
you know, it just didn't work out for us
to move up. So, you know, tomorrow, uh,
I think San Francisco ended up at pick
33, so, you know, they'll pick and then
we're there at 34.
>> Jeremiah Jeremiah said, um, that you
guys were very authentic with him, very
kind-hearted. Just did you get that same
feel with him just immediately talking
to him?
>> He's just a real dude. He's a very, uh,
easy guy to talk to. He's very mature.
Um, like he said, he's got his head on
on straight, you know, and he's about
the right stuff. um comes from a great
family. I think his story is awesome. Uh
but but above all, right right like it's
just like right when he walked in, you
knew you had a man in there, you know,
and uh he loves it. He's smart. He's
tough. He's got all those those
attributes, but uh he's going to be a
good teammate for these guys.
>> Obviously, when you're picking at three,
there's not a ton of scenarios, right?
So, at what point in the process did you
kind of land on the idea that Jeremiah
would would very likely be your guy at
three? Yeah, I mean I think I think we
came to a pretty solid conclusion of
what where we were going, what we were
doing at the start of this week.
>> What did uh Jeremiah's father tell you
about the guy you were considering
drafting? I already had some nice things
to say to both of you.
>> Uh yeah, I don't know that. Yeah, I'm
not sure we either of us spoke to his
father. So
>> absolutely.
>> Yeah. Lonnie, with uh obviously you're
you're looking at scenarios, but but
there was a lot of time between after
your pick and kind of watching how
everything plays out. As you're going
through that, are you guys just honed in
on the round itself? Are you guys
already starting to kind of look ahead
and see what might be there in second
round, etc., etc.?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think I think, you know,
there was a long time to wait there,
Darren. And I think um you know there
was 15 16 picks and and you know you
just kind of sit there and wait. Um you
know I think we had a uh we had a pretty
good idea of what might make it till the
end of the first round and who what guys
we might be considering and then you
know we tried to in our mock draft
exercises we tried to uh go all the way
out to 34 and and see what might be
left. Um but really until it until it
got to a point I mean call it 23 24 25
um you know really didn't have any
discussions about you know you're just
you're forced to wait and see what's
left there. So that happened around I'd
say pick 24 25 and then but nothing came
of it and so we'll be we'll we sat where
we're at. We'll see what happens
tomorrow night. You guys talked last
week about taking players based off not
only where they are, but maybe where
they can be in terms of becoming like an
NFL player. A lot of times like top five
picks are expected to be these franchise
defining guys and game changers and
stuff like that. And he's still a rookie
obviously, but like where do you guys
think Jeremiah can be as an NFL player?
>> I think he can be I think he can help us
in multiple ways. Mike mentioned um as a
runner, as a receiver, in pass
protection. Um, but you know, really
like at this point his his job is to
come in here, uh, meet his teammates,
learn the system, um, you know, meet his
coaches, uh, figure out just how we run
things here and and really that's our
expectation for for him right now.
>> How many mocks do you guys run through
and how accurate are they done with the
first?
>> Um, yeah, it's a great question. Um, we
do we do an exercise on every year on I
think we've done it on Monday or
Tuesday. um where we we utilize our pro
scouts. Um those pro scouts during the
season, they have uh seven or eight
teams that they're they're involved
with. Um and then we just go through the
draft and they they pick players
according to um you know, media reports.
They pick players based on what they
know of the draft. Um, and we just we go
through and then there's there's
scenarios where we'll we'll do one, hey,
do this one, you know, straight straight
down the fairway and then we do another
one. Hey, get a little wild with this
one cuz I mean, as we saw tonight,
there's things that maybe we didn't
anticipate happening. So, that's the
truth with every draft. And, you know,
we we never get it 100% right, but it's
it's a fun exercise to do and and to
just see what might be there. with this
decision-making process. Was ownership
involved in this process in this
decision at all?
>> Uh in the decision? No. No, not at all.
Um you know, Michael um Michael is
involved to the point of uh he likes to
know what's going on. He loves to hear
about our process. He loves to hear
about um how we have arrived at um at
the board where it's at. Um you know,
he's he's great at throwing us scenario.
Well, what if this guy goes, "Okay, well
then we would do this." So, uh,
Michael's been great. He was awesome
with letting Mike and I go through our
process. Um, and he was he was engaged
as always, but really hands off and let
us do our job.
>> Uh, with Jacobe reportedly asking for
the raise, how might that impact
everything moving forward through the
draft and where do you guys currently
stand with him?
>> Yeah, had have had good dialogue. Both
Mike and I have have had good dialogue
with Jacobe. Um, obviously this is the
voluntary portion of everything. Um, you
know, we'll continue to have
conversations with Jacobe, but you know,
things are things are in a good spot.
>> Mike, what are your initial thoughts
when you add a guy with love's talent
level to compliment um Marv, Michael,
Trey?
>> Yeah, just another piece of the puzzle
like you just said. I mean, he's got,
you know, there's like I'm not going to
sit here and say we don't all see the
skill set, obviously, but to add that
skill set to what I already believe is a
pretty good skill set with our receiver
room, with our tight end room, to add to
that running back room. Um, it's it's
cool, you know, and again, like like
Monty said, like the expectation is for
him to come in here, learn the system,
learn his teammates, and get right to
work just like we're asking all these
other guys to do, even the guys that
have, you know, um, done something in
this league. So, uh, I think he's going
to fit in really well with these guys.
But I know he's going to fit in really
well with these guys because again he's
he loves this and and all teammates want
is guys that are going to come in and
help him win and compete and fight hard
and play tough and do all the things
that it takes to move the needle
forward.
>> How different is the prep moving from
round one to rounds two and three going
into the market?
>> Uh you know really not different at all,
Donnie. There's just fewer names left up
on, you know, there's 32 less names on
the board. Um you know, so we'll u we'll
regroup in the morning. um you know, we
already have an idea of the the top two
or three guys that that are on the board
that that we know one of them is going
to be there because there's only one
pick in front of us the second. Um and
then really it's the same, you know,
we'll pick there early in the second or
you know, obviously we'll always listen
if there's any opportunities to move
around. Um and then we got to wait for
32 more names to come off the board
before it's our turn again. So, um
really not different at all. There's
just, you know, fewer and fewer names on
the board as we go.
>> How many picks surprised you today?
>> Say again.
>> How many picks surprised you today? Oh
man, I don't know. There. I mean,
there's always a few.
>> Yeah,
>> there was a few. There was a few, but I
mean, it always happens, you know, like
32 different teams, 32 different boards.
Like, you know, everybody um everybody
sees them a little bit differently.
>> Which one surprised you?
>> Okay.
>> None of them.
His mock hit.
>> 32. 32 out of 32.
>> He won. He won first round bingo. Yeah.
Yeah.
>> You guys should do that. It's a good
game. First round bingo. You write 32
names on the board. First first person
that crossed off all 32 wins for
entertainment purposes only. Of course,
you know.
>> Absolutely.
>> Yeah. That's right. That'd be great.
That'd be great.
>> Friendly wagers.
>> Yeah.
>> Sorry.
>> Yeah. I'll go for for Mike. Like how do
you think a running back can elevate?
like how can an elite running back
elevate an offense and kind of change
the dynamic of the stress you guys are
putting under?
>> Yeah, running back, receiver, tight end.
Like there's no secret in this league,
explosives are are are massive. When you
look at, you know, um outside of
obviously points, like what are the the
two biggest factors statistically? It's
turnovers and explosives. It's actually
closer than you'd think. And so anytime
any way you can generate explosive um
that's a good thing for the offense.
Anytime you can, you know, obviously li
uh limit explosive from a defense,
that's a good thing for the Arizona
Cardinals, you know. So when you bring
in explosive playmakers at any position,
uh you're giving yourself a better
chance to have those explosives. I don't
got to call the greatest play. Sometimes
when you just get the ball to a guy like
Trey McBride, he breaks three tackles
and he turns into explosive. You know,
same thing with our receivers. And so
anytime you can get that from the backs,
it's just that next position that uh
allows you to, like I just said, get
those explosives.
>> Awesome. See you guys tomorrow night.
Yeah. Thank you guys. Thank you.